<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Section Editors on Tropical Plant Pathology</title>
    <link>/tpp/tags/section-editors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Section Editors on Tropical Plant Pathology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tpp/tags/section-editors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TPP among the most rapidly growing Plant Pathology journals based on CiteScore metrics  </title>
      <link>/tpp/post/citescore-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tpp/post/citescore-2018/</guid>
      <description>The latest assessment of scholarly serial publications was made available in early June with the release of the 2017 CiteScore metrics, based on Scopus citation database. A quick analysis of 11 selected similar journals that cover the broad subject of plant pathology shows TPP among three journals with the most increased score (four positions) during the last five years. The current score is 1.07, which is 50% higher than six years earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editorial board meeting during ICPP 2018, Boston </title>
      <link>/tpp/post/editors-meeting-icpp2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tpp/post/editors-meeting-icpp2018/</guid>
      <description>We would like to thank the group of eight Section Editors who could find a time in their busy schedule, during a very big full week meeting in Boston, to sit for an hour and discuss editorial issues. Most of the Editors in the meeting joined TPP late last year, so this was a chance to know them in person and learn from their experiences and answer questions related to the editores duties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet our new Editor for the Mycology Section, Dr. Priscila Chaverri </title>
      <link>/tpp/post/welcome-priscila-chaverri/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tpp/post/welcome-priscila-chaverri/</guid>
      <description>Our Mycology section has a new Editor, Dr. Priscila Chaverri who holds a joint appointment with the University of Maryland and University of Costa Rica. Dr. Chaverri, originally from Costa Rica where she majored in Forestry, holds a PhD in Plant Pathology obtained at The Pennsylvania State University. Her research interests involve the taxonomy of endophytes in the tropics and the systematics of fungal pathogens (Nectriaceae) associated with hardwood trees in both temperate and tropical regions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Denita Hadziabdic Guerry, our new Section Editor </title>
      <link>/tpp/post/welcome-denita/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tpp/post/welcome-denita/</guid>
      <description>Excited to announce Dr. Denita Hadziabdic Guerry as our new Section Editor who will be handling manuscripts in two sections: forest pathology and population biology.
Denita holds an MSc in Plant pathology and Ph.D. in Population Genetics, both obtained at the University of Tennessee. She is an Assistant Professor in the same University with a professional appointment of 90% Research and 10% Teaching. In research, her areas of expertise are Forest health and forest pathology, population genetics of fungal pathogens, population biology, genetic diversity and conservation of native plants.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>