<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tropical Plant Pathology on Tropical Plant Pathology</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tropical Plant Pathology on Tropical Plant Pathology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 23:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates to our editorial policy and instructions for authors</title>
      <link>/post/update-instructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/update-instructions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting in December 2018, TPP will no longer accept for publication first reports of diseases/pathogen in a geographic location. Special cases had been published as short communication, including new diseases in a country, disease of major economic significance for major crops, etc. We will continue to publish original research that is not limited to report the new occurrence of a known disease or pathogen but go beyond including description of new taxa and pathogen population and epidemiological aspects using data from more extensive surveys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We updated our &lt;a href=&#34;/instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions for Authors&lt;/a&gt; and prepared a list of &lt;strong&gt;minimum requirements&lt;/strong&gt; for consideration which should be carefully followed by authors prior to submitting a mansucript to TPP. If at least one of the requirements are not met, the manuscript will be sent back to author.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Manuscripts should contain disease and/or plant pathogen data; please note that &lt;i&gt;first reports of plant diseases/pathogens are no longer accepted under any circumstances&lt;/I&gt;.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Experiments should be repeated in time at least once, unless the research results are from surveys or of non-quantitative nature. Failure to adhere to our experimental and statistical considerations will be grounds for rejection.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Studies on screening or evaluation of efficacy of synthetic/natural products (fungicides, biocontrol agents, plant extracts, etc.) must include field data and provide additional information on modes of action. The latter requirement can be waived if the results are based on meta-analysis using multisite and multi-year datasets and contribute novel information for management. Studies on screening of pathogen populations for drug/fungicide resistance should include in vitro as well as molecular data.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Studies on screening of plant host genotypes for disease resistance should not be limited to ranking locally-adapted genotypes but provide sufficiently novel information on the mechanisms of resistance or other aspects of broader interest to the international plant pathology community.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Submissions must adhere to the manuscript formatting guidelines 

&lt;li&gt;Authors should make sure the manuscript is written in good quality English. Non-native English speakers are encouraged to seek external language editing services if needed. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full documentation of the instructions can be found &lt;a href=&#34;/instructions/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instructions for Authors</title>
      <link>/pages/instructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pages/instructions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last update: 2 December 2018
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Scope&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tropical Plant Pathology is an international journal devoted to publishing a wide range of research on fundamental and applied aspects of plant diseases of concern to agricultural, forest and ornamental crops from tropical and subtropical environments. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Submissions must report original research that provides new insights into the etiology and epidemiology of plant diseases as well as population biology of plant pathogens, host-pathogen interactions, physiological and molecular plant pathology, and strategies to promote crop protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;2. Manuscript submission&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Submission of a manuscript implies that: 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;the work described has not been published before;
&lt;li&gt;it is not under consideration for publication anywhere else; 
&lt;li&gt;its publication has been approved by all co-authors, if any, as well as by the responsible authorities – tacitly or explicitly – at the institute where the work has been carried out. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Neither the publisher nor the society will not be held legally responsible should there be any claims for compensation. See also in this document: &lt;a href=&#34;#ethical-responsibilities-of-authors-16&#34;&gt;Ethical Responsibilities of Authors&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;3. Minimum requirements for consideration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Manuscripts should contain disease and/or plant pathogen data; please note that &lt;i&gt;first reports of plant diseases/pathogens are no longer accepted under any circumstances&lt;/I&gt;.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Experiments should be repeated in time at least once, unless the research results are from surveys or of non-quantitative nature. Failure to adhere to our &lt;a href=&#34;#experimental-and-statistical-considerations-6&#34;&gt;experimental and statistical considerations&lt;/a&gt; will be grounds for rejection.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Studies on screening or evaluation of efficacy of synthetic/natural products (fungicides, biocontrol agents, plant extracts, etc.) must include field data and provide additional information on modes of action. The latter requirement can be waived if the results are based on meta-analysis using multisite and multi-year datasets and contribute novel information for management. Studies on screening of pathogen populations for drug/fungicide resistance should include in vitro as well as molecular data.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Studies on screening of plant host genotypes for disease resistance should not be limited to ranking locally-adapted genotypes but provide sufficiently novel information on the mechanisms of resistance or other aspects of broader interest to the international plant pathology community.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Submissions must adhere to the manuscript formatting guidelines - see more in this document: &lt;a href=&#34;#manuscript-preparation-8&#34;&gt;Manuscript preparation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;#references-11&#34;&gt;References&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;li&gt;Authors should make sure the manuscript is written in good quality English. Non-native English speakers are encouraged to seek external language editing services if needed. See also in this document: &lt;a href=&#34;#english-language-support-18&#34;&gt;English Language Support&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;br&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4. Article types&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Tropical Plant Pathology&lt;/em&gt; considers for publication:

&lt;li&gt; Original Articles
&lt;li&gt; Short Communications
&lt;li&gt; Reviews
&lt;li&gt; Letters to the Editors.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.1 Original article&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;These are full-length papers describing original articles (2,500-3000 words) with the following sections:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Abstract
&lt;li&gt;Introduction
&lt;li&gt;Material and methods
&lt;li&gt;Results
&lt;li&gt;Discussion
&lt;li&gt;Authors&#39; contributions
&lt;li&gt;Acknowledgements
&lt;li&gt;References&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.2 Short communication&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;A straightforward manuscript reporting results that do not warrant a full-length article but that stand on their own (not a preliminary work). Length: up to 2,500 words. The manuscript should present the following sections:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Abstract
&lt;li&gt;Main text
&lt;li&gt;Authors&#39; contributions
&lt;li&gt;Acknowledgements
&lt;li&gt;References&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.3 Review&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Reviews are normally by invitation. However, if you wish to submit one, send a pre-submission enquiry with a tentative title, abstract and evidence of author&#39;s experience in the topic. Reviews can be of three types: narrative literature reviews, systematic reviews, and systematic reviews with meta-analyses.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.4 Letter to the Editor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;Points of view, commentaries or criticisms relating or responding to recent published items of interest to plant pathologists. Discussion on political, social and ethical issues and novel scientific ideas of interest to the journal&#39;s broad readership are also welcome. Length:  up to 1,500 words.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;5. Submission and required files&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The corresponding author, having all files prepared (see below), should submit the manuscript via the Editorial Manager Online system (http://www.edmgr.com/tppa).  &lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Please note that at least three author-suggested reviewers are required to complete submission. These reviewers should be selected in an ethical and unbiased way. See &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.springer.com/gp/authors-editors/authorandreviewertutorials/submitting-to-a-journal-and-peer-review/cover-letters/10285574&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; general guidelines for selecting reviewers appropriately.  
&lt;li&gt;For a new submission, a single file (.doc or .docx) containing the manuscript text, tables and figures is sufficient. There is no need, at this stage, to submit high quality figures (TIFF, PNG, etc.) or tables as separate files. 
&lt;li&gt;Authors are encouraged to submit a cover letter in PDF format or include the text of the letter in the specific field during the submission process. Do recall that a nice cover letter can help to make a good first impression to your work. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.springer.com/gp/authors-editors/authorandreviewertutorials/submitting-to-a-journal-and-peer-review/cover-letters/10285574&#34;&gt;See here &lt;/a&gt; guidelines on how to write a good letter.
&lt;li&gt;Digital files of high quality images and graphs, maps,  etc. should be uploaded only at the last submission after the manuscript is fully revised and close to acceptance. In any case, the typesetting team will further contact authors if uploaded or embedded figures in the doc file are of poor quality.
&lt;li&gt;Electronic Supplemental materials should be uploaded separately – see specific section below.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6. Pre-analysis workflow&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
After submission, the Journal Editorial Office Assistant, who may contact the author and ask for some clarifications or adjustments, performs an operational check. Finally, the Editor-in-Chief or a Senior Editor pre-analyses the submission (prior to assign a Section Editor) to check whether:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
The manuscript falls within the scope;
&lt;li&gt;The minimum requirements are met;
&lt;li&gt;The results are novel and contribute to advance the field;
&lt;li&gt;The quality of language is acceptable for review; 
&lt;li&gt;The manuscript format is prepared following our Instructions for Authors
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6. Experimental and statistical considerations&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
These instructions should be used as a guideline/outline. Researchers should ideally consult with a statistician before designing an experiment and analyzing the data. 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;When conducting observational or planned research choose the most appropriate hypothesis tests for categorical or continuous variables and/or characterize the variability (uncertainty) by means of confidence intervals. These procedures are required to provide evidence of the robustness and reproducibility of the research findings.
&lt;li&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Material and Methods &lt;/em&gt;describe details on how the data were collected including  sampling design and size, number of experimental units (replicates), randomization, blocking and balancing. &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;It is imperative that all experiments are repeated at least once and which criteria was used to pool the data from two experiments for analysis&lt;/span&gt;. For field experiments, at least two trials should be conducted. These can be two years/seasons or two distant sites (different environment) within a same year/season. Manuscripts without evidence of proper design and repetition in time will be rejected.
&lt;li&gt;When analyzing the data, select the most appropriate inferential methods according to the number of groups compared (two or more), independence (non-paired or paired data), type of factor (quantitative or qualitative), and nature of the response variable (continuous, count, categorical or nominal).  &lt;ul&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;When comparing two groups, report &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt;-values using proper t-tests (non-paired or paired) or the equivalent non-parametric tests if assumptions for parametric tests are not met. Alternatively, or additionally, provide 95% confidence intervals for visual inference or calculate the effect-size, in the form of absolute or standardized mean difference between treatments to facilitate interpretation and practical significance of the results. 
 &lt;li&gt;When comparing three or more groups, use parametric analysis of variance (ANOVA) for qualitative data and linear models if the data are continuous (weight, size, area, etc.). For data described as a proportion (incidence), or counts (lesion number) give preference to fit generalized linear models with the appropriate link function to these data. Original data can be transformed prior to analysis, with justifications for the transformation chosen, when using parametric tests. Discrimination among three or more groups can be made using linear contrasts or multiple comparison tests. &lt;em&gt;Duncan&#39;s multiple range test will not be accepted.&lt;/em&gt; 
 &lt;li&gt;Non-parametric tests should be used for ordinal data or disease rating on a 0 to &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt; scale (e.g. 1 = no disease, 2 = leaf distortion; 3 = leaf discoloration, etc.). For ordinal ratings based on disease severity ranges (e.g. Horsfall-Barratt scale), convert the scores to the midpoint of the interval prior to parametric analysis using ANOVA. 
 &lt;li&gt;If there are sufficient time points or number of levels of a quantitative factor (ex.  concentration, temperature etc.), do not use a means separation test to discriminate among levels of the factor. Instead, fit linear or non-linear regression models to the data. Alternatively, for time-dependent (longitudinal) data, consider calculate the area under the curve and compare the mean area among treatments using a means separation test. 
 &lt;li&gt;For correlation analysis, Pearson&#39;s correlation test should be used under the assumption of normality, otherwise use the equivalent non-parametric method such as Spearman&#39;s rank correlation. 
&lt;li&gt;When reporting results of hypothesis tests, give preference to report exact &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt;-values (e.g. &lt;em&gt;t&lt;/em&gt; was significant at &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; = 0.012) or use significance levels when &lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt;-values are very low (&lt;em&gt;P&lt;/em&gt; &lt; 0.001). For data to be presented in a table or a plot/graph make sure to indicate the measure of variability (standard deviation, interquartile range, etc) or inferential statistics (confidence intervals) for values displayed in a table column (or between parentheses) or as error bars in plots. 
&lt;li&gt;Provide the correct citations to all software and packages used for analyzing and preparing data for presentation.  &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;7. Nomenclature and culture collections&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Nomenclature of scientific names should adhere to current international standards for each class of organisms.  &lt;ul&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;Plants: &lt;em&gt;The International Plant Names Index, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ipni.org/index.html&#34;&gt;http://www.ipni.org/index.html&lt;/a&gt;&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Fungi: &lt;em&gt;Index Fungorum&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.speciesfungorum.org/Names/Names.asp&#34;&gt;http://www.speciesfungorum.org/Names/Names.asp&lt;/a&gt;&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Bacteria: &lt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.isppweb.org/names_bacterial.asp&#34;&gt;http://www.isppweb.org/names_bacterial.asp&lt;/a&gt;&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Nematodes: &lt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iczn.org/iczn/index.jsp&#34;&gt;http://www.iczn.org/iczn/index.jsp&lt;/a&gt;&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Viruses: according to the International Code for Virus Classification and Nomenclature, published by the International Committee on Taxonomy of Viruses - ICTV, &lt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ictvonline.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.ictvonline.org&lt;/a&gt;&gt;&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Scientific names should be in full the first time they appear in the body of the text and abbreviated and without authorities later. Whenever a scientific name appears at the beginning of a sentence it must be given in full.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;li&gt;New names for fungi should be deposited in Mycobank, Index Fungorum, Fungal Names or other internationally accepted registration websites and the deposit number informed together with the proposition of the new name.&lt;br&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Source and deposit of cultures and herbarium specimens should be indicated. 
&lt;li&gt;Voucher cultures and specimens documenting their research as well as nucleotide sequences should be deposited at certified or recognized international institutions.&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Accession numbers and place of deposit must be indicated in the text.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;8. Technical names, numbers and unit system&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Only technical names or names of active ingredients should be used. Commercial names of products or of the companies which produce them cannot be used. Chemical formulas should be written on one line and follow standard nomenclature.
&lt;li&gt;International system of units (SI) should be used, such as mg, g, m, mm, L, mL, μL, h, min, s, mol, kg/ha. If a non-standard abbreviation is to be used, it should be defined in full when cited in the text for the first time.
&lt;li&gt;Numbers nine or below must be written out except as part of a date, a fraction or decimal, a percentage, or a unit of measurement. Use Arabic numerals for numbers larger than nine. Avoid starting a sentence with a number, but if doing so write the number out. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;9. Permissions to use copyrighted information &lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
Authors wishing to include figures, tables, or text passages that have already been published elsewhere are required to obtain permission from the copyright owner(s) for both the print and online format and to include evidence that such permission has been granted when submitting their papers. Any material received without such evidence will be assumed to originate from the authors. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;10. Manuscript preparation&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
Manuscript text should be presented in double-spaced paragraphs and 12-point font size throughout all sections, including references. Pages and lines should be numbered consecutively. Page margins should not be too narrow (2.5 cm preferably).
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;10.1 Title page &lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
The title page should include:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A concise and informative title not exceeding 30 words.
&lt;li&gt;The name(s) of the author(s): first and last names in full. 
&lt;li&gt;Corresponding author name and e-mail address - If available, the 16-digit ORCID of the author.
&lt;li&gt;The affiliation(s) of the author(s).  &lt;ul&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;Use superscript numbers to indicate affiliation.
 &lt;li&gt;Affiliation should include department, institute, zip code, city, state/province and country. 
 &lt;li&gt;Multiple affiliations for an author can be used if that is the case or when the author has moved, in this case use the primary affiliation where work was performed and the &#34;present address&#34;. 
 &lt;li&gt;Names of the institution, department, etc. when originally in roman alphabet should be written in the original language. Do not translate institutional names to English, unless there is an official translation.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;10.2 Abstract &lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
The abstract should not exceed 300 words and not contain any undefined abbreviations or unspecified references. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;10.3 Keywords &lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
Please provide 3 to 6 key words; do not repeat words in the title.  Order by scientific names of hosts and/or pathogens and other key words, all in alphabetical order.  
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;10.4 Main text and sections&lt;/h3&gt;

 &lt;ol&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;Note that naming of the main sections of the text (Introduction to Discussion) are required for Original Articles only, not for Short Communications, although the order of the elements is the same. For reviews and letters to Editor, subheadings lead to better organization and facilitates reading. The text of the subheading should be short and specific to the content.
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Introduction:&lt;/em&gt; Description of the background that led to the study, justification, hypothesis which is being tested, if applicable, and objectives.
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Material and Methods:&lt;/em&gt; Detailed description of the materials and procedures used in the research in a way that enables other researchers to repeat exactly the work if willing to do so. Authors should specifically:  &lt;ol&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;Separate and name subsections for better organization
  &lt;li&gt;Not include city and country when citing manufacturers
  &lt;li&gt;Not include trademark symbols when citing commercial products
  &lt;li&gt;Deposit and provide reference numbers of DNA sequence data 
  &lt;li&gt;Explain thoroughly the data analysis procedures, ensuring they are correct and reproduced. 
  &lt;li&gt;Consider making raw data and computational codes available at a repository (or uploaded as supplemental information) for reviewers and latter for readers upon acceptance 
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Results:&lt;/em&gt; This section describes the obtained data and results in a concise and direct manner. As general guidelines:  &lt;ol&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;Whenever the case, begin text presenting inferences based on hypothesis tests 
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid repetition of methodology and state the significance of results 
  &lt;li&gt;Call out data tables and figures with data sequentially. These may appear embed in the document right after the paragraph they are called out.
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discussion: &lt;/em&gt;The findings of the study should be placed in the context of relevant literature. It must not read as literature review with ideas and statements included solely to increase the size of the manuscript. 
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Author contribution statement:&lt;/em&gt; see specific section below.
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Acknowledgments:&lt;/em&gt; a single paragraph to thank people and institutions that provided technical, financial and intellectual support. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;
 &lt;ol&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;References&lt;/em&gt;: listed alphabetically and following our formatting standards. See more in this document:&lt;a href=&#34;#references-11&#34;&gt; References&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;10.5 Author contribution statement&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
Authors must provide a short description of the contributions made by each listed author (please use initials). This should be placed in a separate section before the Acknowledgments. See example below: 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 AA, XX and TT planed, designed and executed experimental work, AA and XX conducted data analyses, AA, XX, TT and ZZ wrote the manuscript.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;10.6 References&lt;/h3&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;10.6.1 General instructions&lt;/h4&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
 Only articles that are published or available online (Online First, Online Early, Early view, etc) in peer-reviewed journals may be cited. Please note that citation of thesis, conference proceedings or technical reports - are no longer accepted. When referencing a personal communication of a non-author of the manuscript, authors must provide appropriate evidence (e-mail). Authors may cite unpublished data of their own. In this case, provide author&#39;s initials and last name followed by &#34;unpublished data&#34;. 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;10.6.2  Citation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Must follow the author/date style, without comma separating the elements. &lt;ul&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;When information is prominent, author&#39;s name is within the parentheses. Example, &#34;An ordinal scale was used to rate disease intensity (Horsfall and Barrat 1945)&#34;. 
 &lt;li&gt;When author is prominent, author&#39;s name is outside the parentheses. Example, &#34;On the other hand, Horsfall and Barrat (1945) proposed a simpler ordinal scale with 12 scores following logarithmic increments&#34;. 
 &lt;li&gt;For two-authors citation, spell out both names separated by &#34;and&#34; (Horsfall and Barratt 1945)
 &lt;li&gt;For citations with three or more authors, name the first author followed by &#34;et al&#34;. &lt;br&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Multiple references in a same citation (using parentheses) should appear in chronological order separated by semicolons.  &lt;ul&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;For references published in the same year, order them alphabetically within the same year by author&#39;s surname.
 &lt;li&gt;For two or more works by the same author in a citation, list them chronologically, with the years separated by semicolons. (Example: Barreto et al. 2006a; 2006b; 2008). &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;10.6.3 Reference list&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ordered alphabetically by the first author surname. &lt;br&gt;

&lt;li&gt;For multiple references for the same author, ordering is as follows:  &lt;ul&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;first, as single author in chronological order
 &lt;li&gt;second, with only one co-author in alphabetical order by the second author
 &lt;li&gt;third, references with more than two co-authors, in alphabetical order by the second or subsequent authors. &lt;br&gt;

&lt;li&gt;In case of more than one publication by the same authors (or authors in the same order) in the same year, add a lowercase letter after the year in alphabetic sequence. &lt;br&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Journal titles should not be abbreviated.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Journal article&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;Reis RF, Goes A, Timmer LW (2006) Effect of temperature, leaf wetness, and rainfall on the production of &lt;em&gt;Guignardia citricarpa&lt;/em&gt; ascospores and on black spot severity on sweet orange. Fitopatologia Brasileira 31:29-34
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Arnold AE, Medjía LC, Kyllo D, Rojas EI, Maynard Z, Robbins N, Herre EA (2003) Fungal endophytes limit pathogen damage in a tropical tree. Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, USA 26:15649-15654
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Book chapter&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;Campos VP, Villain L (2005) Nematode parasites of coffee and cocoa. In: Luc M, Sikora RA, Bridge J (Eds.) Plant parasitic nematodes in subtropical and tropical agriculture. CAB International, Wallingford. pp. 529-580
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Book&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;Agrios GN (2005) Plant Pathology. 5&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Ed. Elsevier Academic Press, Amsterdam
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Edited book&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;Kimati H, Amorim L, Rezende JAM, Bergamin Filho A, Camargo LEA (Eds.) (2005) Manual de Fitopatologia. Vol. 2. Doenças das Plantas Cultivadas. 4 Ed. Ceres, São Paulo
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Online reference&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;CONAB. Cana-de-açúcar, safra 2006 -2007. Available at: http://www.conab.gov.br/BoletimCana.pdf.  Accessed on October 12, 2008
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;11. Tables&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Tables should always be cited in text in consecutive numerical order. 
&lt;li&gt;Tables are to be numbered consecutively using in Arabic numerals.
&lt;li&gt;Each table must start on a new page and be placed after the References section.
&lt;li&gt;A concise title should be provided above the table. 
&lt;li&gt;Each column must have a title in the box head. 
&lt;li&gt;Footnotes typed directly below the table should be indicated preferably in lowercase superscript numbers, but lowercase letters may be used when the column titles contain numbers.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;12. Figures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Figures should be numbered consecutively in Arabic numerals.
&lt;li&gt;Legends should be placed below the figure.
&lt;li&gt;The size of the figures should fit one or two columns.
&lt;li&gt;Special care must be taken with the quality of the images. The commonly used procedure of taking pictures with a digital camera placed above a microscope eyepiece normally yields poor quality images with shaded periphery that are inadequate for publication. 
&lt;li&gt;Details of interest can be shown in pictures with arrows accompanied and explanations of the details in the legend. 
&lt;li&gt;Figures published elsewhere are accepted only if extremely necessary, if proven public domain or accompanied by the permission of the copyright owner(s). Please be aware that some publishers do not grant electronic rights for free and that Springer will not be able to refund any costs that may have occurred to receive these permissions. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;13. Electronic supplementary material&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
Electronic supplementary material will be published in the online version only. It may consist of 
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Information that cannot be embedded in PDF files such as: animations, video clips, sound recordings 
&lt;li&gt;Electronic form data, produced or gathered from other sources for the analysis, of various sizes such as raw experimental data, sequences, spectral data, etc. These data should not be shared as PDF but in the original file: spreadsheets, database, etc. 
&lt;li&gt;Computational codes in the original format, preferably with sufficient comments allowing anyone to reproduce the analysis.
&lt;li&gt; Before submitting research datasets as electronic supplementary material, authors should read the journal&#39;s Research data policy. We encourage research data to be archived in data repositories wherever possible. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Submission &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Supply all supplementary material in standard file formats.
&lt;li&gt;Please include in each file the following information: article title, journal name, author names; affiliation and e-mail address of the corresponding author.
&lt;li&gt;To accommodate user downloads, please keep in mind that larger-sized files may require very long download times and that some users may experience other problems during downloading. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Numbering &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;If supplying any supplementary material, the text must make specific mention of the material as a citation, similar to that of figures and tables.
&lt;li&gt;Refer to the supplementary files as &amp;ldquo;Online Resource&amp;rdquo;, e.g., &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; as shown in the animation (Online Resource 3)&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; additional data are given in Online Resource 4&amp;rdquo;.
&lt;li&gt;Name the files consecutively, e.g. &amp;ldquo;ESM_3.mpg&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;ESM_4.pdf&amp;rdquo;. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Captions &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;For each supplementary material, please supply a concise caption describing the content of the file. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Processing of supplementary files &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Electronic supplementary material will be published as received from the author without any conversion, editing, or reformatting. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;14. After acceptance&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Upon acceptance of your article you will receive a link to the special Author Query Application at Springer&amp;rsquo;s web page where you can sign the Copyright Transfer Statement online and indicate whether you wish to order OpenChoice and offprints. Once the Author Query Application has been completed, your article will be processed and you will receive the proofs.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;15. Color illustrations &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Publication of color illustrations is free of charge.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;16. Proof reading &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The purpose of the proof is to check for typesetting or conversion errors and the completeness and accuracy of the text, tables and figures. Substantial changes in content, e.g., new results, corrected values, title and authorship, are not allowed without the approval of the Editor. After online publication, further changes can only be made in the form of an Erratum, which will be hyperlinked to the article.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;16. Online First &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The article will be published online after receipt of the corrected proofs. This is the official first publication citable with the DOI. After release of the printed version, the paper can also be cited by issue and page numbers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;17. Copyright transfer &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Authors will be asked to transfer copyright of the article to the Publisher (or grant the Publisher exclusive publication and dissemination rights). This will ensure the widest possible protection and dissemination of information under copyright laws.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;18. Open Choice&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Open Choice allows you to publish open access in more than 1850 Springer Nature journals, making your research more visible and accessible immediately on publication. Benefits:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Increased researcher engagement: Open Choice enables access by anyone with an internet connection, immediately on publication.
&lt;li&gt;Higher visibility and impact: In Springer hybrid journals, OA articles are accessed 4 times more often on average, and cited 1.7 more times on average*.
&lt;li&gt;Easy compliance with funder and institutional mandates: Many funders require open access publishing, and some take compliance into account when assessing future grant applications.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Article processing charge&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Open access publishing is not without costs. As of January 7 2019 an article processing charge (APC) of 2480 EUR/ 3140 USD/ 2080 GBP net will be charge from authors who wish to make their articles open access in the journal. The APC will be levied after article acceptance.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
If you are looking for funding support open access please see our funding and support page for more information: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.springer.com/gp/open-access/open-access-funding&#34;&gt;https://www.springer.com/gp/open-access/open-access-funding&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Copyright and license term – CC BY &lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Open Choice articles do not require transfer of copyright as the copyright remains with the author. In opting for open access, the author(s) agree to publish the article under the Creative Commons Attribution License.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Creative Commons Attribution License: &lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0&#34;&gt;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;19. Research data policy&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
The journal encourages authors, where possible and applicable, to deposit data that support the findings of their research in a public repository. Authors and editors who do not have a preferred repository should consult Springer Nature&amp;rsquo;s list of repositories and research data policy.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.springernature.com/gp/group/data-policy/repositories&#34;&gt;List of Repositories&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.springernature.com/gp/group/data-policy/faq&#34;&gt;Research Data Policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;General repositories&lt;/strong&gt; - for all types of research data - such as figshare and Dryad may be used where appropriate.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Datasets that are assigned digital object identifiers (DOIs) by a data repository may be cited in the reference list. Data citations should include the minimum information recommended by DataCite: authors, title, publisher (repository name), and identifier.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.datacite.org/&#34;&gt;DataCite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
Springer Nature provides a research data policy support service for authors and editors, which can be contacted at researchdata@springernature.com.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
This service provides advice on research data policy compliance and on finding research data repositories. It is independent of journal, book and conference proceedings editorial offices and does not advise on specific manuscripts.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.springernature.com/gp/group/data-policy/helpdesk&#34;&gt;Helpdesk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;20. Ethical responsibilities of authors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
This journal is committed to upholding the integrity of the scientific record. As a member of the Committee on Publication Ethics (COPE) the journal will follow the COPE guidelines on how to deal with potential acts of misconduct.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Authors should refrain from misrepresenting research results which could damage the trust in the journal, the professionalism of scientific authorship, and ultimately the entire scientific endeavour. Maintaining integrity of the research and its presentation can be achieved by following the rules of good scientific practice, which include:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;The manuscript has not been submitted to more than one journal for simultaneous consideration. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;The manuscript has not been published previously (partly or in full), unless the new work concerns an expansion of previous work (please provide transparency on the re-use of material to avoid the hint of text-recycling (&amp;ldquo;self-plagiarism&amp;rdquo;). &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;A single study is not split up into several parts to increase the quantity of submissions and submitted to various journals or to one journal over time (e.g. &amp;ldquo;salami-publishing&amp;rdquo;). &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;No data have been fabricated or manipulated (including images) to support your conclusions.&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;No data, text, or theories by others are presented as if they were the author&amp;rsquo;s own (&amp;ldquo;plagiarism&amp;rdquo;). Proper acknowledgements to other works must be given (this includes material that is closely copied (near verbatim), summarized and/or paraphrased), quotation marks are used for verbatim copying of material, and permissions are secured for material that is copyrighted. Important note: the journal may use software to screen for plagiarism. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Consent to submit has been received explicitly from all co-authors, as well as from the responsible authorities - tacitly or explicitly -at the institute/organization where the work has been carried out, before the work is submitted. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Authors whose names appear on the submission have contributed sufficiently to the scientific work and therefore share collective responsibility and accountability for the results. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Authors are strongly advised to ensure the correct author group, corresponding author, and order of authors at submission. Changes of authorship or in the order of authors are not accepted &lt;strong&gt;after&lt;/strong&gt; acceptance of a manuscript. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Adding and/or deleting authors and/or changing the order of authors at revision stage may be justifiably warranted. A letter must accompany the revised manuscript to explain the reason for the change(s) and the contribution role(s) of the added and/or deleted author(s). Further documentation may be required to support your request. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Requests for addition or removal of authors as a result of authorship disputes after acceptance are honored after formal notification by the institute or independent body and/or when there is agreement between all authors. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;Upon request authors should be prepared to send relevant documentation or data in order to verify the validity of the results. This could be in the form of raw data, samples, records, etc. Sensitive information in the form of confidential proprietary data is excluded.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If there is a suspicion of misconduct, the journal will carry out an investigation following the COPE guidelines. If, after investigation, the allegation seems to raise valid concerns, the accused author will be contacted and given an opportunity to address the issue. If misconduct has been established beyond reasonable doubt, this may result in the Editor-in-Chief&amp;rsquo;s implementation of the following measures, including, but not limited to:
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;If the article is still under consideration, it may be rejected and returned to the author. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;If the article has already been published online, depending on the nature and severity of the infraction, either an erratum will be placed with the article or in severe cases complete retraction of the article will occur. The reason must be given in the published erratum or retraction note. Please note that retraction means that the paper is maintained on the platform, watermarked &amp;ldquo;retracted&amp;rdquo; and explanation for the retraction is provided in a note linked to the watermarked article. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;li&gt;The author&amp;rsquo;s institution may be informed.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;21. English language support &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
If you need help with writing in English you should consider using a professional language editing service where editors will improve the English to ensure that your meaning is clear and identify problems that require your review. Two such services are provided by our affiliates Nature Research Editing Service and American Journal Experts.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://secure.authorservices.springernature.com/en/default/submit/select/1/6/manuscript/_/_&#34;&gt;Nature Research Editing Service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://secure.aje.com/en/default/submit/select/1/6/manuscript/_/_&#34;&gt;American Journal Experts&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Please note that the use of a language editing service is not a requirement for publication in this journal and does not imply or guarantee that the article will be selected for peer review or accepted.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TPP among the most rapidly growing Plant Pathology journals based on CiteScore metrics  </title>
      <link>/post/citescore-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/citescore-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The latest assessment of scholarly serial publications was made available in early June with the release of the 2017 CiteScore metrics, based on Scopus citation database. A quick analysis of 11 selected similar journals that cover the broad subject of plant pathology shows TPP among three journals with the most increased score (four positions) during the last five years. The current score is 1.07, which is 50% higher than six years earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src = &#34;/img/posts/citescore2017.png&#34; style = &#34;margin-bottom:30px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This rapid growth may be due to some changes in the period including publication of papers only in English language (2012), which allowed to increase the number of international Editors. In 2015, TPP has been published by Springer Nature. We are thankful to all Editors and anonymous reviewers who dedicate time and contribute to the quality of the articles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editorial board meeting during ICPP 2018, Boston </title>
      <link>/post/editors-meeting-icpp2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/editors-meeting-icpp2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src = &#34;/img/posts/editors-pic-icpp2018.jpg&#34; style = &#34;margin-bottom:30px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would like to thank the group of eight Section Editors who could find a time in their busy schedule, during a very big full week meeting in Boston, to sit for an hour and discuss editorial issues. Most of the Editors in the meeting joined TPP late last year, so this was a chance to know them in person and learn from their experiences and answer questions related to the editores duties. From left to right, Denita H. Guerry, Nik Cunniffe, Alessandra Souza, Rodrigo Almeida, Sydney Everhart, Diana Fernandez, Zhang Hao, Emerson Del Ponte and Adam Sparks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a productive meeting with several comments and suggestions made by the Editors to improve the quality of the work we publish. These included an enhanced database of reviewers, editorial board structure, special issues, criteria of acceptance, statistical issues, etc. We are happy to have a committed group of Editors  willing to contribute the most to make TPP the number one journal for tropical plant diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meet our new Editor for the Mycology Section, Dr. Priscila Chaverri </title>
      <link>/post/welcome-priscila-chaverri/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/welcome-priscila-chaverri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src = &#34;/img/posts/chaverri1.jpg&#34; style = &#34;margin-bottom:30px&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Mycology section has a new Editor, Dr. Priscila Chaverri who holds a joint appointment with the University of Maryland and University of Costa Rica. Dr. Chaverri, originally from Costa Rica where she majored in Forestry, holds a PhD in Plant Pathology obtained at The Pennsylvania State University. Her research interests involve the taxonomy of endophytes in the tropics and the systematics of fungal pathogens (Nectriaceae) associated with hardwood trees in both temperate and tropical regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Chaverri is an experienced Editor for international journals including Mycological Progress, Phytopathology and Revista Forestal Mesoamericana Kurú (Costa Rica). In 2013 she was awarded the
C. J. Alexopolous award given by the Mycological Society of America to &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;an outstanding mycologist early in their career.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome Priscila and appreciate her willingness to collaborate with Tropical Plant Pahtology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Institutional webpages:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://psla.umd.edu/people/dr-priscila-chaverri&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;University of Maryland&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://micologia.biologia.ucr.ac.cr/Chaverri.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;University of Costa Rica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Denita Hadziabdic Guerry, our new Section Editor </title>
      <link>/post/welcome-denita/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/welcome-denita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src = &#34;/img/posts/denita1.jpg&#34; style = &#34;margin-bottom:30px&#34;&gt;Excited to announce Dr. Denita Hadziabdic Guerry as our new Section Editor who will be handling manuscripts in two sections: forest pathology and population biology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Denita holds an MSc in Plant pathology and Ph.D. in Population Genetics, both obtained at the University of Tennessee. She is an Assistant Professor in the same University with a professional appointment of 90% Research and 10% Teaching. In research, her areas of expertise are Forest health and forest pathology, population genetics of fungal pathogens, population biology, genetic diversity and conservation of native plants. In teaching, she offers the course called Special Problems in Entomology, Nematology, and Plant Pathology – Population Genetics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome Denita and appreciate her willingness to collaborate with TPP. More information at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://epp.tennessee.edu/people/directory/dr-denita-hadziabdic-guerry&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Department webpage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our new website was launched!</title>
      <link>/post/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src = &#34;/img/posts/screen_site.png&#34; style = &#34;margin:30px&#34; align=right&gt;Excited to announce our new modern and responsive website with an improved interface and updated content. We added a news blog section where we will write posts of interest to academic researchers and keep authors and readers up to date with Tropical Plant Pathology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the several improvements in this version, we will be soon prepare a simplified version of our instructions for authors a FAQ section with the most frequently questions received from the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a new section with detailed information and links to academic webpages or each of our 23 Section Editors from a total of 11 countries. Untill the mid the year we will have new page which will allow searching our archives of articles published from 1976 to 2000 year. During the last two years individual PDFs for the articles were prepared and cataloged using Mendeley. An interface will be available to filter by year and search author and title fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you enjoy our website!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Embed your slides or video here using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;. Further details can easily be added using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/project/deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Duis posuere tellus ac convallis placerat. Proin tincidunt magna sed ex sollicitudin condimentum. Sed ac faucibus dolor, scelerisque sollicitudin nisi. Cras purus urna, suscipit quis sapien eu, pulvinar tempor diam. Quisque risus orci, mollis id ante sit amet, gravida egestas nisl. Sed ac tempus magna. Proin in dui enim. Donec condimentum, sem id dapibus fringilla, tellus enim condimentum arcu, nec volutpat est felis vel metus. Vestibulum sit amet erat at nulla eleifend gravida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nullam vel molestie justo. Curabitur vitae efficitur leo. In hac habitasse platea dictumst. Sed pulvinar mauris dui, eget varius purus congue ac. Nulla euismod, lorem vel elementum dapibus, nunc justo porta mi, sed tempus est est vel tellus. Nam et enim eleifend, laoreet sem sit amet, elementum sem. Morbi ut leo congue, maximus velit ut, finibus arcu. In et libero cursus, rutrum risus non, molestie leo. Nullam congue quam et volutpat malesuada. Sed risus tortor, pulvinar et dictum nec, sodales non mi. Phasellus lacinia commodo laoreet. Nam mollis, erat in feugiat consectetur, purus eros egestas tellus, in auctor urna odio at nibh. Mauris imperdiet nisi ac magna convallis, at rhoncus ligula cursus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cras aliquam rhoncus ipsum, in hendrerit nunc mattis vitae. Duis vitae efficitur metus, ac tempus leo. Cras nec fringilla lacus. Quisque sit amet risus at ipsum pharetra commodo. Sed aliquam mauris at consequat eleifend. Praesent porta, augue sed viverra bibendum, neque ante euismod ante, in vehicula justo lorem ac eros. Suspendisse augue libero, venenatis eget tincidunt ut, malesuada at lorem. Donec vitae bibendum arcu. Aenean maximus nulla non pretium iaculis. Quisque imperdiet, nulla in pulvinar aliquet, velit quam ultrices quam, sit amet fringilla leo sem vel nunc. Mauris in lacinia lacus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suspendisse a tincidunt lacus. Curabitur at urna sagittis, dictum ante sit amet, euismod magna. Sed rutrum massa id tortor commodo, vitae elementum turpis tempus. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Aenean purus turpis, venenatis a ullamcorper nec, tincidunt et massa. Integer posuere quam rutrum arcu vehicula imperdiet. Mauris ullamcorper quam vitae purus congue, quis euismod magna eleifend. Vestibulum semper vel augue eget tincidunt. Fusce eget justo sodales, dapibus odio eu, ultrices lorem. Duis condimentum lorem id eros commodo, in facilisis mauris scelerisque. Morbi sed auctor leo. Nullam volutpat a lacus quis pharetra. Nulla congue rutrum magna a ornare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aliquam in turpis accumsan, malesuada nibh ut, hendrerit justo. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Quisque sed erat nec justo posuere suscipit. Donec ut efficitur arcu, in malesuada neque. Nunc dignissim nisl massa, id vulputate nunc pretium nec. Quisque eget urna in risus suscipit ultricies. Pellentesque odio odio, tincidunt in eleifend sed, posuere a diam. Nam gravida nisl convallis semper elementum. Morbi vitae felis faucibus, vulputate orci placerat, aliquet nisi. Aliquam erat volutpat. Maecenas sagittis pulvinar purus, sed porta quam laoreet at.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Project</title>
      <link>/project/example-external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/example-external-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Person Re-Identification System For Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>/publication/person-re-identification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/person-re-identification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile visual clothing search</title>
      <link>/publication/clothing-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/clothing-search/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
